CURRICULUM VITAE



Dr. David Muchangi Mugo

Ph.D (Information Systems), MSc (Computer Science), MBA (Technology Management), BSc (Computer Science), CCNA Instructor, IBM Certified Big Data Instructor, ISO 27001:2013 auditor, ISO 9001: 2015 auditor

Chairman, Academic Leader and Lecturer,

Department of Mathematics, Computing & IT, University of Embu P.O Box 6 - 60100, Embu, Kenya Phone:+254 719 574060

Email: davemugo2005@yahoo.co.uk

Career Objective

To become a distinguished Professor of Information Systems and to work whole heartedly to positively impact on the society for improvement of humanity and our environment

1. Personal Information

Nationality: Kenyan

Date of Birth: 23rd April 1982

Home Address: P.O Box 526-060100, Embu, Kenya

Marital Status: Married

Languages: Kiswahili: Excellent, English: Excellent, German: Good

National ID No: 22526395

Passport No: B213545

2. Brief Resume

Dr. David Muchangi Mugo, a Kenyan Citizen, is a PhD holder of Information Systems from Kenyatta University, Kenya. He has a Master's of Science (MSc) Degree in Computer Science from Technical University of Hamburg, Germany and a Masters of Business Administration (MBA) where he specialized in technology management from Northern Institute of Technology Management, Hamburg, Germany. Dr. David Mugo has been a lecturer for more than nine years and is currently lecturing at the University of Embu, Kenya. Additionally, he is the current Chairman, Department of Mathematics, Computing and Information Technology (MCIT), University of Embu. Further, he is the coordinator, Website and Electronic Repository at the University where he has propelled the University towards higher Universities' Webometrics Ranking. He is a married man and a father of two boys.

3. Education

01/2013 – 12/2016: Kenyatta University, Nairobi, Kenya

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) in Information Systems

Courses Undertaken: Economic Analysis for Business Decisions (Grade: B), Statistics for Business I (Grade: A), Business Research Methods (Grade: A), Statistics for Business II (Grade: A), Data Analysis and Measurement (Grade: A), Strategic Information Systems (Grade: A), Advanced Topics in Information Systems (Grade: B), Seminar in Management Information Systems (Grade:

A), Independent Study in Information Systems (Grade: A)

Thesis Title: Mobile Technology Services and Performance of

Deposit-Taking SACCOs in Kenya (Grade: B)

Date of Graduation: 16th December 2016

02/2013 - 06/2013: Kenyatta University Cisco Networking Academy, Nairobi, Kenya

CCNA Instructors Course

10/2007 – 1/2010: Hamburg University of Technology (TUHH), Germany

Masters of Science (MSc) in Computer Science specializing in

Information and Media Technologies

Thesis Title: Connecting people using Latent Semantic Analysis for

Knowledge Sharing

Date of Graduation: 27th January 2010

Grade: 2.3

10/2007 - 5/2010:

9/2002 - 4/2007:

Northern Institute of Technology Management (NIT), Germany

Masters of Business Administration (MBA) specializing in

Technology Management

Date of Graduation: 30th May 2010

Grade: 2.1

Kenyatta

University, Nairobi, Kenya

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Date of Graduation: 13th April 2007

Grade: First Class Honours

2/1997 – 11/2000: Moi High School Mbiruri, Embu, Kenya

Kenya Certificate of Secondary School (KCSE)

Grade: A- (Minus)

2/1988- 11/1996: Kagumori Primary School, Embu, Kenya

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education (KCPE)

Marks: 499/700

4. Employment History

02/2017 – To Date: University of Embu

Duties: Lecturer in the Department of Mathematics, Computing and

Information Technology

University Responsibilities

Coordinator-Website and E-Repository

Chairman - Department of Mathematics, Computing and IT

4/2014- 01/2017: University of Embu

Duties: Assistant Lecturer, Department of Mathematics, Computing

and Information Technology

University Responsibilities

Coordinator-Website and E-Repository

Chairman - Department of Mathematics, Computing and IT

03/2012 – 03/2014: Kenyatta University

Duties: Assistant Lecturer in the Department of Computing & IT

05/2011 - 04/2014: Zetech University

Duties: Part-Time Lecturer in Computer Science

01/2011 – 02/2012: The Presbyterian University of East Africa, Kenya

Duties: Lecturer in the School of Computer Science

01/2010 - 7/2010: Warwick Business School, Coventry, United Kingdom

Duties: Consultant on eHealth for a European Commission

4/2009 - 12/2009: Grindaix GmbH, Aachen, Germany

Duties: Research on investigation of Latent Semantic Analysis (LSA)

in connecting people for knowledge sharing

8/2008 - 2/2009: Körber Ag, Hamburg, Germany

Duties: Research on developing Knowledge Management Models

4/2006 - 5/2007: Mansoft Limited, Nairobi, Kenya

Duties: Software development (Payroll and Human Resources)

5/2005 - 9/2005: Kenya Railways Corporation, Nairobi, Kenya

Duties: Networking, programming, computer repair & maintenance

1/2004 - 2/2005: Emanex Computer College, Nairobi, Kenya

Duties: Part-time tutor, Computer maintenance and Networking

5. Appointments and Responsibilities

April 2019 – To Date: External Examiner, Faculty of Business Computer Science and

Communication Studies, St. Paul's University, Limuru, Kenya

Duties: Checking quality of examination drafts, ensuring marking meets high integrity standards and guiding on examination integrity matters.

April 2019 – To Date: Member, University's Knowledge Management Committee

Duties: acquiring, preservation and dissemination of University's institutional knowledge

March 2017 - To Date: Member, University of Embu, ISO Committee

Duties: Ensuring that the University conforms to quality standards as per implemented Quality Management Systems while advising the University on new ISO standards

March 2017 – To Date: External Examiner, Faculty of IT, Zetech University

Duties: Checking quality of examination drafts, ensuring marking meets high integrity standards and guiding on examination integrity matters.

Feb 2017 – To Date: Member, University Mentorship Committee

Duties: Mentoring students and staff members in the University

Jan 2017 – To Date: Chairman, Department of Mathematics, Computing and Information

Technology (MCIT), University of Embu

Duties: Directing and overseeing all administrative and academic matters in the Department

Oct 2013 – To Date: Coordinator, Website and E-Repository

Duties: Marketing the University through the Website, improving University Webometrics Ranking, Collating, storing and consolidating all publications made by the University and its staff

6. Publications, Conferences, Seminars and Workshops

6.1 Publications

2019: Mugo David, Muathe Stephen and Waithaka Stephen (2019).

Performance Analysis of Debit Card Services on Deposit-Taking SACCOs' Financial Performance: A Case of Kenya. *The African*

Journal of Information Systems, Vol. 12, No. 2, pp. 117-132

2018:

Mugo David, Muathe Stephen and Waithaka Stephen (2018).

Effect of mobile communication services on performance of SACCOs in Kenya. *European Scientific Journal, Vol.14, No.30*

ISSN: 1857 – 7881 (Print) e - ISSN 1857- 7431

2017: Mugo David, Muathe Stephen and Waithaka Stephen (2017).

Moderating Effect of Government Policies on the Relationship between Mobile Technology Services and Performance of Deposit-Taking Saccos in Kenya. *International Journal of Scientific*

Engineering and Technology, Volume No.6 Issue No.2, pp: 71-74

2014: Mugo David and Nzuki David (2014). Determinants of Electronic

Health in Developing Countries. International Journal of Arts and

Commerce, Vol. 3 No. 3

2010: Mugo David (2010). Connecting people using Latent Semantic

Analysis for Knowledge Sharing. Master Thesis. The paper is

available online at: http://www.sts.tu-harburg.de/pw-and-m-

theses/papers.html

2009: Mugo David (2010). An investigation of the Latent Semantic

Analysis Technique for Document Retrieval. Studentarbeit (Student

Project). The paper is available online at: http://www.sts.tu-

harburg.de/pw-and-m-theses/papers.html

6.2 Conferences

26th – 27th March 2018 Mugo David, Muathe Stephen and Waithaka Stephen (2018).

Effect of debit card services on financial performance of Deposit-Taking SACCOs in Kenya. 2nd Annual Conference on Innovations for Sustainable Co-operative Development, Co-operative University of Kenya, Nairobi

1st -3rd November 2017: Mugo David, Muathe Stephen and Waithaka Stephen (2017).

Effect of mobile communication services on performance of Deposit-Taking SACCOs in Kenya. The 3rd International Conference on Science, Technology, Innovation and Entrepreneurship, Dedan Kimathi University of Technology

1st – 4th August 2017: Mugo David, Muathe Stephen and Waithaka Stephen (2017).

Effect of Mobile Web Services on Performance of Deposit-Taking SACCOs in Kenya. *The 4th International Interdisciplinary Conference (IIC4 2017), Kyambogo University, Kampala Uganda*

27th – 28th March 2017: Mugo David, Muathe Stephen and Waithaka Stephen (2017).

Effect of mobile banking services on financial performance of Deposit-Taking cooperative societies in Kenya. *International*

Conference on Entrepreneurship, Business and

Technology (ICEBUT), Accra, Ghana

2nd December 2016: Mugo David (2017). Mobile Technology Services and Performance

of Deposit-Taking SACCOs. Postgraduate Seminar held at Kenyatta

University, Nairobi, Kenya.

6.3. Seminars and Workshops

11th – 15th March 2019: Attended IBM Big Data training which was held in KENET Training

Lab within the University of Nairobi main campus, did examination

and was certified as an IBM Big Data Instructor

19th April 2018: Attended Credit Risk Management Seminar held at Eton Hotel –

Thika, Kenya facilitated by Kenya Union of Savings & Credit Co-

operative LTD.

14th -16th Feb 2018: ISO 27001:2013 Internal Auditors Training facilitated by Maier

Consulting Limited

5th – 7th Feb 2018: ISO 9001:2015 Internal Auditors Training facilitated by Maier

Consulting Limited

22nd June 2017: Attended a Workshop on Administrative Strategies for Effective

Management of a Department in a University at the University of

Embu

20th-21st June 2017: Attended a Seminar on Environmental Impact Assessment and

Environmental Audit facilitated by NEMA at the University of Embu

25th May 2017: Attended the 1st Annual Postgraduate Seminar held at the University

of Embu

15th – 17th May 2017: Attended an ISO 27001:2013 Information Security Management

System (ISMS) Implementation Course at the University of Embu

facilitated by Maier Consulting Limited.

15th – 16th May 2017: Attended an Intellectual Property (IP) Training at the University of

Embu organized by the University of Embu in conjuction with the

Kenya Industrial Property Institute (KIPI)

9th – 11th May 2017: Attended an ISO 9001:2015 Quality Management System (QMS)

Implementation Course at the University of Embu facilitated by

Maier Consulting Limited.

20th April 2017: Attended a workshop on Grant Writing held at the University of

Embu facilitated by National Research Fund

13th Dec 2016: Attended a workshop on Postgraduate Supervision at the University

of Embu. Topic for the workshop: "Effective Supervision, Objective

	Examination & Mentorship of Postgraduate Studies"		
8 th -9 th May 2016:	Attended a workshop at the University of Embu. Topic for the		
	workshop: "Training on curriculum development and		
	implementation"		
16 th -17 th July2015	Attended a workshop at the University of Embu. Topic for the		
	workshop: "Proposal and thesis writing workshop"		
20 th -23rd Feb 2014:	Attended Annual Seminar of the KAAD Association of Scholars		
	from East Africa (KASEA) held at Arusha, Tanzania. Theme for the		
	seminar: "Nature knows no Borders- Natural Resource Management		
	in Regional Perspective"		
28 th - 14 th Nov 2013:	Seminar on teaching, setting and marking examinations methodology,		
	held at Kenyatta University, Kenya.		
	Participation level: Participant as a lecturer		
1st – 4th Aug 2013:	Attended Annual Seminar of the KAAD Association of Scholars		
	from East Africa (KASEA) held at Nairobi Kenya. Theme for the		
	seminar: "communion in African Communities"		
23rd – 25th Nov 2012:	Attended Annual Seminar of the KAAD Association of Scholars		
	from East Africa (KASEA) held at Kampala Uganda. Theme for the		
	seminar: Towards East African Integration: Regionalization as a		
	New Space for Social and Economic Change		

7. Postgraduate Supervision

S/NO Student Name PhD Students	Thesis/Project Title	University	Status
1. Jeniffer Jepkoech	A Novel Image Processing Approach for Detection, Segmentation and classification of Plant Leaf Diseases: A case study of Coffee in Kenya.	-	Proposal Stage
MSc Students			
2. Maurice Murimi	A classification model of maize plant leaves disease using artificial neural network	Karatina University	Data Collectio n Stage
3. Waweru Loise Wanjiru	A Framework on Blockchain technology for land and real estate records in Kenya	University of Embu	Proposal Stage

4. Edwin Kiprono Serem

Hybrid Model for implementation of University Proposal Blockchanin technology in secure and of Embu Stage

aagile mobile money transfer in Kenya

8. Competencies

Technical Skills: CSS, MySQL, XML, XPATH, XSL, XQuery, Servlets, AJAX,

Tomcat, Design Patterns, WebServices, Eclipse, SQL Server, Communication Networks, Software Architecture, Network Security,

Application Security and JSP

Soft Skills: Controlling, Business Strategy, Economics, Finance, Human

Resources, Project Management, Supply Chain Management, Conflict Management, Procurement and Production Management,

and Accounting

Programming Pascal, Java, C++, C, PHP, MATLAB, Visual Basic 6.0, Delphi 7.0

Languages:

9. Honours and Awards

2007: "Global Engineering" MBA Scholarship by Thomas Matzen GmbH,

to study Masters in Business Administration in Hamburg, Germany

2007: Katholischer Akademischer Austauschdienst (KAAD), 2-year

scholarship to study MSc in Computer Science at Hamburg

University of Technology, Germany

2004: Awarded for being the Best Computer Science Student in Kenyatta

University by Korean Embassy

2000: Awarded a Certificate for being the best student in Embu District,

Kenya

2000: Awarded a Certificate for participating in the Provincial Science

Congress

10. Community Service

2018-To Date: Board Member and Chairman, Credit Committee, Embuvarsity

SACCO

2017-To Date: Secretary, Kamiu Catholic Church, Embu

2017-To Date: Vice Secretary, Embu Parish Catholic Church

2015-2017: Chairman, Development Committee, Rutune Catholic Church, Embu

11. Hobbies

Mentorship: Mentoring young people and giving motivational talks in schools

Physical Hobbies: Jogging, dancing and travelling

Reading: Reading articles on current affairs, Bible and Motivational Books

12. Referees

1. Prof. Kiplagat Kotut, Deputy Vice Chancellor(ARE), University of Embu, P.O Box 793-60100, Embu. Tel: +254 722288471, Email: kotut.kiplagat@embuni.ac.ke

2. Dr. Elizaphan Maina Muuro- Lecturer, Computing and Information Technology Department, Kenyatta University, P.O Box 43844-00100, Nairobi. Tel: +254722508793

3. Dr. Millien Kawira, Dean, School of Pure and Applied Sciences, University of Embu, P.O Box 6 - 60100, Embu. Tel: +254727450027, Email: kawira.millien@embuni.ac.ke

I CERTIFY THAT ALL INFORMATION STATED IN THIS RESUME IS TRUE AND COMPLETE TO THE BEST OF MY KNOWLEDGE. I AUTHORIZE THE CONCERNED PARTY TO VERIFY THE INFORMATION PROVIDED IN THIS RESUME

Dr. David Muchangi Mugo